St. Alban's "Super Sixties Program" Oral History Project OHP019
People's Archive, MLK Library
St. Alban's "Super Sixties Program" Oral History Project
1976-1979
People's Archive, MLK Library
St. Alban's Episcopal Church
OHP019
7.75 Linear feet
Scope and Contents
Between 1976 and 1979, members of St. Alban's Episcopal church parish conducted over 100 oral history interviews with older residents of the District of Columbia. This project conducted listening interviews in which the interviewee was asked to review their lives and to pass on to others whatever they wished to share of their experience. The project director was Sara Jenkins and it was partly funded by a grant from the Advisory Neighborhood Commission 3-C.
Biographical / Historical
St. Alban's Parish is an Episcopal church in Washington, D.C. that was founded in 1854.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
St. Alban's Episcopal Church conducted these interviews between 1976 and 1979 and transferred the collection to the Library in the early 1980s. There is no deed of gift for this collection.
Oral History
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews.
  - Blanche Freeman, 1976 February 11 (Box 1, Folder 18-01)
  - Shanley Agnes, 1976 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 18-02)
  - Flora Brown, 1976 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 18-03)
  - Grace Latona, 1976 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 18-04)
  - Guy Killian, Wilfred McClaren, Blanche Freeman, 1976 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 18-05)
  - Guy Killian, Wilfred McClaren, Blanche Freeman, 1976 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 18-05)
  - Guy Killian, 1976 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 18-06)
  - Blanche Freeman, 1976 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 18-07)
  - Shirley Fenner, 1976 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 18-07)
  - Esther Harris, 1976 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 18-08)
  - Elizabeth Smith, 1976 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 18-09)
  - Faith Tilton, 1977 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 18-10)
  - Guy Killian, 1977 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Charlotte Keyser, 1977 February 22 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Grace Houchen, 1977 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Hilda Crenshaw, 1977 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Esther Harris, 1977 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Irene Rice, 1977 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Vernice Waters, 1977 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - H. Cecil Kilpatrick, 1977 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Helen Benson, 1977 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Ruth Wise (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Florence Stewart, 1977 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Vernice Waters, 1977 July 26 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Bill Whitlock, 1977 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Jenny McGill, 1977 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Nettie Ottenberg, 1977 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Gladys Wall, 1977 August 2 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Rose Berman, 1977 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Wilfred McClaren, 1977 August 17 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Bea Trussell, 1977 August 29 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Cornelia Hamilton, 1977 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - John Wunsch, 1977 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Mary Ward, 1977 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Miriam Leahy, 1977 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Louise Garner, 1977 October 5 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Gertrude Johns, 1978 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Vernice Waters, 1978 January 24 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Andrew Dick, 1978 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - John Robinson, 1978 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Philip Stone, 1978 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Carl Bush, 1978 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Gershom Bradford, 1978 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Lyman Green, 1978 January 24 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Harold Colborn (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Larry Jackson, 1977 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Elizabeth Daiger, 1978 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Gertrude Hibbard (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Andrew Cherrico, 1978 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Mary S. Bond, 1977 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Edwin L. Peterson, 1978 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Evelyn Anderson (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Rhoda Armstrong, 1978 February (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Perry Simms, 1978 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Louise Willoughby, 1978 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Faith L. Oliphant (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Dorothy Boyd Johnson, 1978 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Mabel, Staupers, 1978 March 29 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Frances Foltz, 1978 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Selma Kallis, 1978 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Claire Cornell (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Samuel Danley, 1978 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Marie Giddens, 1978 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Paul Giddens, 1978 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Katie Bell (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Katherine Pagan, 1978 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Eleanor Walker (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Peter Leary (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Albert Raymond (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Earl Dickson, 1978 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Anna Burgers (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Minnie Burke (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Lillian Morrison (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - John Tomlinson (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Earl Dickson, 1978 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Robert D. Langley, 1979 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
  - Rea Hayes, 1978 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 18-11)
- Series 2: Interviews
  - Blanche Freeman, 1976 February 11
  - Shanley Agnes, 1976 May 12
  - Flora Brown, 1976 July 13
  - Flora Brown, 1976 July 13
  - Grace Latona, 1976 July 10
  - Grace Latona, 1976 July 10
  - Guy Killian, Wilfred McClaren, Blanche Freeman, 1976 October 26
  - Guy Killian, Wilfred McClaren, Blanche Freeman, 1976 October 26
  - Guy Killian, Wilfred McClaren, Blanche Freeman, 1976 November 10
  - Guy Killian, 1976 September 30
  - Blanche Freeman, 1976 June 14
  - Shirley Fenner, 1976 February 21
  - Shirley Fenner, 1976 February 21
  - Grace Latona
  - Agnes Shanley, 1976 November 16
  - Elizabeth Smith, 1976 December 2
  - Faith Tilton, 1977 January 31
  - Marie Thomas, 1977 February 9
  - Bill Rohrman, 1977 February 9
  - Guy Killian, 1977 February 17
  - Charlotte Keyser, 1977 February 22
  - Grace Houchen, 1977 March 11
  - Hilda Crenshaw, 1977 March 12
  - Esther Harris, 1977 February 18
  - Irene Rice, 1977 March 11
  - Vernice Waters, 1977 April 4
  - H. Cecil Kilpatrick, 1977 April 6
  - Helen Benson, 1977 May 25
  - Ruth Wise
  - Florence Stewart, 1977 June 23
  - Florence Stewart, 1977 June 23
  - Vernice Waters, 1977 July 26
  - Bill Whitlock, 1977 July 22
  - Jenny McGill, 1977 July 13
  - Nettie Ottenberg, 1977 July 27
  - Gladys Wall, 1977 August 2
  - Rose Berman, 1977 March 21
  - Wilfred McClaren, 1977 August 17
  - Jeanne Dixon, 1977 August 25
  - Nettie Ottenberg, 1977 August 9
  - Bea Trussell, 1977 August 29
  - H. Cecil Kilpatrick, 1977 August 25
  - Margaret Packer, 1977 August 2
  - Cornelia Hamilton, 1977 September 19
  - John Wunsch, 1977 September 8
  - Mary Ward, 1977 September 23
  - Miriam Leahy, 1977 October 4
  - Louise Garner, 1977 October 5
  - Gertrude Johns, 1978 January 3
  - Vernice Waters, 1978 January 24
  - Andrew Dick, 1978 January 10
  - John Robinson, 1978 January 23
  - Cornelia Hamilton, 1978 January 30
  - Philip Stone, 1978 February 15
  - Carl Bush, 1978 February 8
  - Gershom Bradford, 1978 February 24
  - Gershom Bradford, 1978 February 24
  - Lyman Green, 1978 January 24
  - Harold Colborn
  - Larry Jackson, 1977 October 31
  - Elizabeth Daiger, 1978 January 25
  - Gertrude Hibbard
  - Andrew Cherrico, 1978 March 14
  - Mary S. Bond, 1977 December 1
  - Edwin L. Peterson, 1978 March 17
  - Evelyn Anderson
  - Rhoda Armstrong, 1978 February
  - Rhoda Armstrong, 1978 February
  - Rhoda Armstrong, 1978 February
  - Perry Simms, 1978 January 11
  - Louise Willoughby, 1978 March 15
  - Faith L. Oliphant
  - Faith L. Oliphant
  - Dorothy Boyd Johnson, 1978 March 20
  - Mabel, Staupers, 1978 March 29
  - Frances Foltz, 1978 April 7
  - Frances Foltz, 1978 April 7
  - Selma Kallis, 1978 February 17
  - Selma Kallis, 1978 February 17
  - Selma Kallis, 1978 February 17
  - Selma Kallis, 1978 February 17
  - Claire Cornell
  - Samuel Danley, 1978 April 3
  - Marie Giddens, 1978 March 30
  - Paul Giddens, 1978 March 21
  - Paul Giddens, 1978 March 21
  - Katie Bell
  - Katherine Pagan, 1978 April 25
  - Katherine Pagan, 1978 April 25
  - Eleanor Walker
  - Peter Leary
  - Albert Raymond
  - Albert Raymond
  - Albert Raymond
  - Albert Raymond
  - Frances Foltz, 1978 May 6
  - Earl Dickson, 1978 April 18
  - Anna Burgers
  - Anna Burgers
  - Anna Burgers
  - Minnie Burke
  - Minnie Burke
  - Lillian Morrison
  - John Tomlinson
  - John Tomlinson
  - Earl Dickson, 1978 July 6
  - Robert D. Langley, 1979 February 28
  - Carolyn Bingham, 1979 February 2
  - Della R. Dixon, 1978 January 9
  - Paul Brindle, 1979 April 26
  - Minnie Burke, 1978 November 29
  - L. Newton Hayes, 1978 October 30
  - L. Newton Hayes, 1978 October 30
  - Gary Shumway
  - Gary Shumway
  - Gary Shumway